Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Drama, Production Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Drama, production photographs
1896-1969
PC0007
Stanford University. Department of Drama.
8.5 Linear feet (approximately 4700 photographic prints)
This collection consists of photographs taken by anonymous amateur photographers and some local professional photographers of drama department theatrical productions, as well as some student productions such as the Gaieties. The majority date from 1920 to 1960.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Biographical/Historical note
The drama department was one of the original departments of Stanford University. Its first formally produced theatrical, "Sleeping Car", was given December 31, 1891.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of photographs taken by anonymous amateur photographers and some local professional photographers of drama department theatrical productions, as well as some student productions such as the Gaieties. The majority date from 1920 to 1960.
Access Terms
Cole, Wendell; Stanford University. Department of Drama.; Drama; Drama Productions; Drama Student Productions Misc.; Drama--Study and teaching--California--Stanford.; Dramatics.; Stanford University--Dramatics.
Collection Contents
- Photographs
  - Accent on Youth, 1950 (Box 1)
  - The Adding Machine, 1929 (Box 1)
  - The Adding Machine (negatives), 1929 (Box 1)
  - The Alchemist, 1954 (Box 1)
  - All's Well that Ends Well (Box 1)
  - Amphitryon 38, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Androcles, 1925 (Box 1)
  - The Angel of the Lord, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Antigone, 1902 (Box 1)
  - Antigone, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Antigone, 1902 (Box 1)
  - Antigone, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Antony and Cleopatra (Box 1)
  - Any Number Will Do, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Anything Goes, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Aren't We All, 1927 (Box 1)
  - L'Arlès Enne (Box 1)
  - Arms and the Man (See Also Oversize), 1930 (Box 1)
  - Arms and the Man (Box 1)
  - Arms and the Man, 1946 (Box 1)
  - As You Like It, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Baby-Face O'Flynn, 1949 (Box 1)
  - The Bartered Bride, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Beautiful People, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Beggar on Horseback, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Beggar's Opera (Box 1)
  - Billy Budd, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Biography (Box 1)
  - Bird in Hand, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Blue Bird (Box 1)
  - The Book of Charm, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Boy Meets Girl, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Broadway, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Build No Fence (Box 1)
  - The Butler Commands, 1913 (Box 1)
  - Caesar and Cleopatra (Box 2)
  - Calderon Contra Ramsey, 1902 (Box 2)
  - Call Me Madam, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Camille In Roaring Camp, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Camino Real (Box 2)
  - Candida (Box 2)
  - Captain Applejack, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Charley's Aunt (Box 2)
  - Cherry Orchard, 1950 (Box 2)
  - The Circle, 1957 (Box 2)
  - The Circle, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Climate of Eden (Box 2)
  - The Comedy of Errors (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Yankee
  - Counterpoint May (Box 2)
  - Cretan Woman (Box 2)
  - Cyrano de Bergerac, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Cyrano de Bergerac (negatives), 1951 (Box 2)
  - Cyrano de Bergerac, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Daises on the Car Tracks (Box 2)
  - Dangerous Corner, 1956 (Box 2)
  - The Deadly Game, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Dear Brutus, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Death Takes a Holiday, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Death Watch, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Design in Theatre Exhibition, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Desire Under the Elms, 1952 (Box 2)
  - The Devil and Daniel Webster (Box 2)
  - The Devil's Daughter (See Also Oversize) (Box 2)
  - Devil's Disciple, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Dock Brief, 1963 (Box 2)
  - A Doll's House (See Also Oversize) (Box 2)
  - Don Juan by Moliere, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Do Re Mi (Box 2)
  - The Dover Road, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Duley, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Dybbuk, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Eagle With Two Heads, 1964 (Box 3)
  - East Wall, West Wall, 1963 (Box 3)
  - The Egg Woman, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Electra, 1960 (Box 3)
  - The Enchanted Cottage, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Endgame, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Enemy of the People, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Eve of St. Mark, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Everyman, 1907 (Box 3)
  - Expressing Willie, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Everyman in His Humor- English Club, 1905 (Box 3)
  - Falstaff (Opera by Verdi), 1953 (Box 3)
  - The Far Off Hills (Box 3)
  - Fashion (includes 1 Photo from 1926 Production), 1956 (Box 3)
  - The Father (See Also Oversize), 1947 (Box 3)
  - The First Born, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Fore, 1923 (Box 3)
  - Der Freischütz (Box 3)
  - Gaieties, 1934 (Box 4)
  - The Girl and the Voice, 1913 (Box 4)
  - Girl of the Golden West, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Goat Song, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Golden Apple, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Gondoliers (Box 4)
  - Good Woman of Setzuan, 1952 (Box 4)
  - The Governor's Wife, 1938 (Box 4)
  - The Great Divide, 1939 (Box 4)
  - The Green Goddess, 1926 (Box 4)
  - Gringo's Gamble, 1938 (Box 4)
  - The Hairy Ape, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Hamlet, 1926 (Box 4)
  - Hamlet, 1963 (Box 4)
  - The Hasty Heart (Box 4)
  - Hay Fever, 1927 (Box 4)
  - Hay Fever, 1943 (Box 4)
  - He Who Gets Slapped, 1942 (Box 4)
  - He Who Gets Slapped, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Hedda Gabler (Box 4)
  - Hell Bent for Heaven (Box 4)
  - Henry IV- Part I (Box 4)
  - Her Masters Voice (Box 4)
  - High Tor (Box 4)
  - A Highland Fling (See Also Oversize), 1945 (Box 4)
  - Hippolytus, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Der Hofmeister, 1963 (Box 4)
  - The Hostage, 1963 (Box 4)
  - House of Bernarda Alba (Box 4)
  - I am a Camera, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Ice Bound, 1924 (Box 5)
  - I Knock at the Door, 1959
  - Importance of Being Ernest (Box 5)
  - In The Next Room, 1926 (Box 5)
  - In Time to Come (Box 5)
  - Intimate Relations, 1961 (Box 5)
  - An Intimate Review (Box 5)
  - Iolanthe, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Iphigenia in Taurus by Euripides, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Iphigenia in Taurus (Opera), 1963 (Box 5)
  - Is Life Worth Living, 1944 (Box 5)
  - Jason (Box 5)
  - John Doe, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Julius Caesar, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Jumping Frog of Calaveras County (Box 5)
  - Junior Theatricals, 1925 (Box 5)
  - Knickerbocker Holiday, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Knight of the Burning Pestle, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Knight of the Burning Pestle, 1903 (Box 5)
  - Knight of the Burning Pestle, 1903 (Box 5)
  - Knightie Knight, 1924 (Box 5)
  - The Lady and the Burglar, 1913 (Box 6)
  - Lady Precious Stream, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Lady Windemere's Fan, 1953 (Box 6)
  - The Late George Apley (Box 6)
  - A Leap-Year Leap, 1920 (Box 6)
  - Let's Pretend, 1924 (Box 6)
  - The Little Foxes (Box 6)
  - Long Day's Journey into Night, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Love for Three Oranges, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Love Labour's Lost, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Lysistrata, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Macbeth, 1925 (Box 6)
  - Macbeth (See Also Oversize), 1946 (Box 6)
  - Macbeth, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Mademoiselle Colombe, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Madwoman of Chaillot (Box 6)
  - The Magic Flute
  - Magic in the Sky, 1957 (Box 6)
  - The Maids, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Major Barbara, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Male Animal (Box 6)
  - Man and Superman, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Man and Superman, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Man is Man, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Man Who Woke Up, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Marco Millions, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Marriage of Mr. Mississippi, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Mary of Scotland (Box 6)
  - The Mask and the Face, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Master of Santiago, 1961 (Box 6)
  - The Matchmaker, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Measure For Measure, 1962 (Box 7)
  - The Measure Taken, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Medea, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Meet the Wife, 1921 (Box 7)
  - Merchant of Venice, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Merry Wives of Windsor (See Also Oversize), 1945 (Box 7)
  - Midsummer Night's Dream, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Milestones, 1925 (Box 7)
  - Misalliance, 1955 (Box 7)
  - The Miser, 1946 (Box 7)
  - The Miser, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Mr. Congressman (Box 7)
  - The Mistress of Briary, 1935 (Box 7)
  - The Mistress of the Inn, 1930 (Box 7)
  - A Moment of Suspense, 1913 (Box 7)
  - The Moon Besieged, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Moor Born, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Morning At Seven (See Also Oversize), 1946 (Box 7)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Murder in the Cathedral, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Murder in the Cathedral, 1952 (Box 7)
  - My Heart's in the Highlands, 1947 (Box 7)
  - My Indian Family (See Also Oversize) (Box 7)
  - Night Flight (Opera), 1962 (Box 7)
  - Nightmare Abby (Box 7)
  - No More Peace, 1949? (Box 7)
  - No Trifling With Love, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Northwest Drama Conference, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Not Herbert, 1929 (Box 7)
  - Now I Lay Me Down to Sleep, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Oedipus Rex, 1924 (Box 8)
  - Of Mice and Men (Box 8)
  - Of Thee I Sing, 1940 (Box 8)
  - Oh Where Has All Our Money Gone (Box 8)
  - One Acts- The Happy Journey, Hello Out There, Village Wooing, 1943 (Box 8)
  - One Acts- The Enemy, Papa Traverses,Rehabilitation, 1946 (Box 8)
  - One Acts- Winter's End, Fumed Oak, Scheming Lieutenant, 1946 (Box 8)
  - One Acts, 1947 (Box 8)
  - One Acts, 1948 (Box 8)
  - One Acts, 1955 (Box 8)
  - One Acts, 1961 (Box 8)
  - One Acts- Profissa Taranne, Breasts of Tireseus, 1962 (Box 8)
  - One Hundred Acres and a Man, 1951 (Box 8)
  - One Sunday Afternoon, 1934 (Box 8)
  - One of the Family, 1929 (Box 8)
  - The Oresteia, 1948 (Box 8)
  - The Oresteia, 1951 (Box 8)
  - The Original Miss Tewksbury, 1907 (Box 8)
  - Orpheus Descending, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Othello, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Out of this World, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Pappa Is All (See Also Oversize), 1944 (Box 8)
  - La Parisienne, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Passage to Rome, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Peer Gynt, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Peter Grimes, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Petrified Forest, 1949 (Box 8)
  - Pinafore, 1896 (Box 8)
  - The Play of the Ages, 1925 (Box 8)
  - The Play's the Thing, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Playboy of the Western World, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Polly With a Past, 1925 (Box 8)
  - The Poor of New York, 1941 (Box 8)
  - Portrait From Memory, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Princess Ida, 1927 (Box 8)
  - The Princess of Leeland, 1903 (Box 8)
  - The Question, 1956 (Box 9)
  - Rain (Box 9)
  - Rain From Heaven, 1941 (Box 9)
  - Rake's Progress (Box 9)
  - Rambling Rameses, 1912 (Box 9)
  - Red Sky At Night, 1952 (Box 9)
  - The Relapse (Box 9)
  - Resounding Tinkle Bedtime Story, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Return of Peter Grime, 1949 (Box 9)
  - Richard II, 1940 (Box 9)
  - Richard II, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Richard III (Box 9)
  - Ride a Cock Horse, 1926 (Box 9)
  - The Rivals (Box 9)
  - Road to Rome, 1930 (Box 9)
  - Romantic Young Lady, 1928 (Box 9)
  - Romeo and Juliet (See Also Oversize), 1932 (Box 9)
  - The Room, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Rosmersholm, 1964 (Box 9)
  - The Royal Family, 1931 (Box 9)
  - The Royal Family, 1947 (Box 9)
  - R.U.R., 1924 (Box 9)
  - St. Joan (See Also Oversize), 1941 (Box 9)
  - School For Husbands (See Also Oversize), 1944 (Box 9)
  - School For Scandal (See Also Oversize), 1946 (Box 9)
  - Sea Gull (See Also Oversize), 1945 (Box 9)
  - Sea Gull, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Second Threshold (Box 9)
  - Second Shepherd's Plan, 1961 (Box 9)
  - La Serea, 1907 (Box 9)
  - Servants of Two Masters, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Shadow and Substance, 1939 (Box 9)
  - She Stoops to Conquer, 1925 (Box 9)
  - She Stoops to Conquer, 1940 (Box 9)
  - Sherwood (See Also Oversize), 1915 (Box 9)
  - The Shoemaker's Holiday, 1939 (Box 9)
  - The Shoemaker's Prodigious Wife (Box 9)
  - Shootki (See Also Oversize), 1947 (Box 9)
  - Short Plays, 1961 (Box 9)
  - The Showoff (See Also Oversize), 1945 (Box 9)
  - This Side Idolatry, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Six Characters In Search of An Author, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Six Characters In Search of An Author, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Skin Of Our Teeth, 1954 (Box 10)
  - The Snob, 1963 (Box 10)
  - South Seas Preferred, 1928 (Box 10)
  - Squaring the Circle, 1943 (Box 10)
  - Star Wagon, 1940 (Box 10)
  - A Storm, A Tiger, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Street Scene, 1949 (Box 10)
  - Suddenly Last Summer, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Sun-Up, 1929 (Box 10)
  - The Swan, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Sweet Bird of Youth, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Taming of the Shrew (See Also Oversize) (Box 10)
  - Tartuffe, 1942 (Box 10)
  - The Tempest, 1939 (Box 10)
  - The Tempest, 1954 (Box 10)
  - There and Back Opera, 1962 (Box 10)
  - They Knew What They Wanted (Box 10)
  - Thieves' Carnival, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Three Cuckolds, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Three Men on a Horse, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Three Penny Opera (Box 10)
  - The Three Sisters, 1940 (Box 10)
  - Thunder Rock, 1941 (Box 10)
  - Tiger at the Gates, 1957 (Box 10)
  - The Time of Your Life, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Time Remembered, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Tobias and the Angel, 1938 (Box 10)
  - Tonight at 8:30, 1943 (Box 10)
  - A Touch of the Poet, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Tovarich, 1939 (Box 10)
  - The Trial, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Trial By Jury, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Trinumus, 1899 (Box 11)
  - The Trojan Women, 1937 (Box 11)
  - The Truth About Blayds, 1944 (Box 11)
  - Turn Down an Empty Glass, 1952 (Box 11)
  - Twelfth Night, 1910 (Box 11)
  - Twelfth Night, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Twelfth Night, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Two Gentlemen of Verona, 1964 (Box 11)
  - Uncle Vanya, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Under Milkwood, 1960 (Box 11)
  - The Unknown Woman (Box 11)
  - Venus Observed (Box 11)
  - The Vikings In Helgeland, 1938 (Box 11)
  - Volpone, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Waltz of the Toreadors, 1961 (Box 11)
  - The Warrior's Husband, 1940 (Box 11)
  - Well of the Saints, 1959 (Box 11)
  - What Price Glory?, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Where the Dear Antelope Play, 1941 (Box 11)
  - Wicked William, 1927 (Box 11)
  - The Wild Duck, 1941 (Box 11)
  - The Wild Duck, 1957 (Box 11)
  - The Wind and the Rain, 1942 (Box 11)
  - Winter One Acts, 1958 (Box 11)
  - Winterset, 1948 (Box 11)
  - The Wookey, 1942 (Box 11)
  - The Yellow Jacket, 1922 (Box 11)
  - You and I, 1926 (Box 11)
  - You and I (Box 11)
  - You Never Can Tell, 1909 (Box 11)
  - You Never Can Tell, 1954 (Box 11)
  - You Touched Me, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Young Man Of Today, 1949 (Box 11)
  - Zoo Story, 1962 (Box 11)
  - List of Plays Produced in Memorial Hall, 1937-1942 (Box 12)
  - Lady Precious Stream, 1937 (Box 12)
  - This Side Idolatry, 1937 (Box 12)
  - Twelfth Night, August 1937 (Box 12)
  - Murder in the Cathedral, October 1937 (Box 12)
  - Trial By Jury, October 1937 (Box 12)
  - Don Juan, November 1937 (Box 12)
  - The Alchemist, November 1937 (Box 12)
  - The Trojan Women, December 1937 (Box 12)
  - The Governor's Wife, January 1938 (Box 12)
  - Winter's Tale, February 1938 (Box 12)
  - Nursing Maid of Heaven, February 1938 (Box 12)
  - The Vikings in Helgeland, March 1938 (Box 12)
  - Star Wagon, April 1938 (Box 12)
  - Kind Lady, April 1938 (Box 12)
  - Johnny Johnson. May 1938 (Box 12)
  - Camille of Roaring Camp, July 1938 (Box 12)
  - Uncle Tom's Cabin, August 1938 (Box 12)
  - Gringo's Gamble, August 1938 (Box 12)
  - Tobias and the Angel, December 1938 (Box 12)
  - Mask and the Face, February 1939 (Box 12)
  - Hippolytus, February 1939 (Box 12)
  - All's Well that Ends Well, March 1939 (Box 12)
  - Tovarich, April 1939 (Box 12)
  - The Shoemaker's Holiday, April 1939 (Box 12)
  - No More Peace, May 1939 (Box 12)
  - The Tempest, 12965 (Box 12)
  - The Two Shepards, August 1939 (Box 12)
  - Night Before the Boarder, August 1939 (Box 12)
  - The Great Divide, October 1939 (Box 12)
  - Shadow and Substance, November 1939 (Box 12)
  - The Dream Play, November 1939 (Box 12)
  - The Warrior's Husband, February 1940 (Box 12)
  - George and Margaret, February 1939 (Box 12)
  - Richard II, May 1940 (Box 12)
  - Richard III (Box 12)
  - The Headless Horseman, May 1940 (Box 12)
  - Mr. Congressman, October 1940 (Box 12)
  - The Poor of New York, October 1940 (Box 12)
  - Of Thee I Sing, November 1940 (Box 12)
  - Saint Joan, January-February 1941 (Box 12)
  - Rain From Heaven, February 1941 (Box 12)
  - The Bartered Bride, March 1941 (Box 13)
  - The Comedy of Errors, April 1941 (Box 13)
  - Hay Fever, May 1941 (Box 13)
  - Where the Dear Antelope Play, 1941 (Box 13)
  - Thunder Rock, 1941 (Box 13)
  - Far Off Hills, 1941 (Box 13)
  - Knickerbocker Holiday, 1941 (Box 13)
  - Marco's Millions, 1942 (Box 13)
  - The Beggar's Opera, 1942 (Box 13)
  - The Wind and the Rain, 1942 (Box 13)
  - He Who Got Slapped, 1942 (Box 13)
  - Daises on the Car Tracks, 1942 (Box 13)
  - Tartuffe, 1942 (Box 13)
  - Drama Department Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 13)
  - Dramatics-Unidentified Productions (Box 13)
  - Unidentified Negatives (Box 13)
  - Unidentified Photographs [1 of 2] (Box 13)
  - Unidentified Photographs [2 of 2] (Box 13)
  - Unidentified Color Transparencies (Box 13)
  - Unidentified Black-and-White 8x10 Negatives (23)
    Nitrate negatives--RESTRICTED
    - K-130 (Box 14)
    - K-131 (Box 14)
    - K-140 (Box 14)
    - K-141 (Box 14)
    - K-142 (Box 14)
    - K-143 (Box 14)
    - K-144 (Box 14)
    - K-145 (Box 14)
    - K-146 (Box 14)
    - K-147 (Box 14)
    - K-148 (Box 14)
    - K-149 (Box 14)
    - K-150 (Box 14)
    - K-151 (Box 14)
    - K-152 (Box 14)
    - K-153 (Box 14)
    - K-154 (Box 14)
    - K-155 (Box 14)
    - K-156 (Box 14)
    - K-157 (Box 14)
    - K-158 (Box 14)
    - K-159 (Box 14)
  - Album “Plays of 1921 and Before", 1913-1921 (Box 15)
  - Album “Plays from 1915-1921” including an image of Gordon Davis (Box 15)
  - Album “Season of 1921-1922” (Box 16)
  - Album “Season of 1922-1923” including an image of Delmer Daves (Box 16)
  - Album “Season of 1923-1924” (Box 16)